# Setumadhava Giridhar Kathawate

Product Designer With A Passion For Solving People's Problems.

206-739-4983 setugk8@gmail.com Seattle, WA <u>www.setumadhava.com</u>

# About

Product designer having 3 years of experience in designing products, seeking opportunities to solve complex user and business problems through elegant, research-informed product and experience designs. Other interests include Machine Learning, Behavioral Psychology and Cooking.

# Skills

**Primary UX Skills**: Interaction Design, Prototyping, Visual design, Framer, InVision, Sketch, Product Strategy, Project Scoping, Cross-functional Collaboration, Agile Development Process, Remote and Inperson User Research Methods, Usable Product Design, HTML/CSS.

**Meta Skills**: Awareness, Responsibility and Ownership, Integrity, Decision making, Resourceful, Critical thinking, Problem solving, Constant learning.

# Experience

#### **UX DESIGNER, UW MEDICINE**

**DEC 2017 - PRESENT** 

Designed web and mobile experiences as a part of UW Medicine's website redesign efforts.

**Key Accomplishment**: Owned the responsibility and delivered 14 high-fidelity, production-ready web and mobile screen mockups in 2 days, after the contracted design agency failed to deliver the designs on-time. As a result, there were no delays in the project timelines.

#### **CO-FOUNDER AND PRODUCT DESIGNER, EVENTOSAUR**

**MAR 2015 - PRESENT** 

Leading a distributed team of designers and non-designers to build a SaaS product to solve the problem of order, inventory and team management for event vendors in India.

**Key Accomplishment**: Co-founded a profitable event-planning start-up and worked remotely while in grad school to design a web-app that solved the problem of vendor discovery and reduced the complexity in traditional event planning for millennials in India.

#### **UX DESIGNER, PREMERA BLUE CROSS**

**MAY 2017 - DEC 2017** 

Led the UX efforts to design a Provider Search tool to help Premera's customers confidently find the providers or facilities covered by their insurance plan.

**Key Accomplishment**: Average customer satisfaction score went up from 2.8 to 4.1 (on a scale of 1-5) after shipping the new search experience.

#### INTERACTION DESIGN INTERN, EXPEDIA INC

**JUN 2016 - SEP 2016** 

Conceptualized and designed a mobile web interface to explore alternative hotel shopping experience for Expedia's customers by simplifying the beds and occupancy preferences, room browsing and checkout process.

**Key Learnings**: Collaboration in a large UX Organization, designing for accessibility, cross-functional collaboration, project and time management.

## Education

### MASTER'S IN HUMAN CENTERED DESIGN AND ENGINEERING

SEP 2015 - MAR 2017

The University of Washington, Seattle; GPA 3.92/4.0

**Relevant Courses**: User-Centered Design, Usability Studies, Data Science for UX Researchers, Visual Communication, Interaction Design and Prototyping, Machine Learning (Coursera).

#### **BACHELOR'S IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING**

AUG 2006 - JUN 2010

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bangalore, India; GPA 6.9/10.0

# **Awards**

BEST GRADUATE CAPSTONE PROJECT - PUMP IT UP

**JUN 2017** 

University of Washington, Seattle

Explored solutions to reduce water waste in Indian homes by designing an Android app + IOT system that provides contextual information and better control over existing water systems to the residents.